Lucas Petherbridge

Principal Software Engineer

Passionate & driven polyglot Software Engineer with 12+ years experience designing innovative solutions using the latest software technologies and practices. Started as a self-taught programmer at age 15 and am constantly seeking to expand and grow. Great communicator and team collaborator willing to take on any challenge.

Contact Info



Work Experience

Email

me@lukeworks.tech

Website

lukeworks.tech

GitHub

github.com/lukexor

LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/lucaspetherbridge

Technologies

- Rust, Golang, C/C++, Python
- JavaScript/Typescript, NodeJS, React/NextJS, HTML, CSS
- NGINX, MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB
- Microsoft Azure, Docker, Kubernetes

Lithia Motors, Inc.

2 yrs 2 mos · Portland, OR

Principal Software Engineer

Jan 2022 - Present · 8 mos

- Curated a suite of libraries and packages aligning company standards including a UI template and NPM package that doubled project delivery speed.
- Led architecture initiative for 7 teams, increasing website performance by 100% using LighthouseCI and PageSpeed Insights by migrating to NextJS.

▶ Staff Software Engineer

Jul 2021 - Jan 2022 · 6 mos

 Provided technical leadership to 6 teams by scheduling learning sessions, pair programming & writing extensive documentation.

Senior Software Engineer

Jul 2020 - Jul 2021 · 1 yr

- Designed & implemented customer authentication platform for an automotive ecommerce website using Auth0, React & Typescript deployed with Microsoft Azure & Kubernetes.
- Increased team testing coverage for unit & end-to-end tests from zero to 60% using Jest & Cypress.



TEKsystems - Consultant at Nike

3 mos · Beaverton, OR

▶ Senior Software Engineer

Mar 2020 - Jun 2020 · 3 mos

- Designed & configured cloud infrastructure as code for a GraphQL API using Okta authentication, AWS & Terraform.
- Exit: Contract ended due to organization restructure.



NetFortris (Formerly Fonality, Inc)

6 yrs 4 mos · Culver City, CA

▶ Senior Software Engineer

Nov 2013 - Mar 2020 · 6 yrs 4 mos

- Redesigned Salesforce integration using modern technologies reducing project size by 90% by switching from Angular to Vue.js using JavaScript, Vue.js, & XML.
- Designed & developed an OSS/BSS for the ordering, billing, & provisioning of telephony services which led to a 20% increase in revenue using Perl, JavaScript, JQuery & HTML/CSS.



Education



Portland State University

Bachelor of Computer Science 2015 – 2019 · Portland, OR

 Provided Scrum & Agile Practice consultation services for 10 teams during my senior capstone.



Projects

PixEngine

Sep 2019 - Present

A cross-platform graphics & UI library for simple games, visualizations, and graphics application written in Rust. https://lukeworks.tech/pix-engine

TetaNES

Mar 2019 - Present

A cross-platform & web-browser emulator for the Nintendo Entertainment System (NES) written in Rust & Typescript supporting WebAssembly. https://lukeworks.tech/tetanes

Personal Portfolio/Blog

May 2022 - Present

A personal blog & project portfolio website using React/NextJS & Typescript. https://lukeworks.tech/